<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Aljan Scholtens</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Aljan Scholtens</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A part of Hermanshöhen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/part-of-hermanshohen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/part-of-hermanshohen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every six months, I go on a multi-day hiking trip in the Netherlands with a friend of mine (Patrick). But this time, we wanted to go just across the border. That led us to the Hermanshöhen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Less than an hour and a half in the car, and you find yourself in the beautiful Teutoburgerwald. It’s been over a year since we were there, but since I forgot to post the video on my blog—here it is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My minimal phone experiment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/my-minimal-phone-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/my-minimal-phone-experiment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For years I have considered my phone an annoying distraction. Ten years ago, I wrote briefly about this in &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aljanscholtens.nl/blog/afleiding-maakt-dom&#34;&gt;Distraction makes you stupid&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;. While a phone does &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2021/07/210702154317.htm&#34;&gt;not make you dumber&lt;/a&gt;, we recognize that its use can cause problems with focusing and unwinding. This piece does not delve deeply into studies, but is an account of my umpteenth experiment to find more calm and peace in daily life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;dumb-phone&#34;&gt;Dumb Phone&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have been fantasizing about a life without a smartphone for a few years now, longing for a minimal or dumb phone. My need for rest during long walks and real moments of relaxation is hampered by my iPhone in my pocket. Quickly looking something up in the browser, sending a friend a message or checking for an email from a potential client - it seems inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donjon from Age of Empires 2 in Lego</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/lego-donjon-moc-age-empires-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/lego-donjon-moc-age-empires-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My friends are organizing an annual Age of Empires 2 (AoE2) online tournament, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ageofgamers.nl&#34;&gt;Age of Gamers&lt;/a&gt;, which was started during the pandemic. During this year&amp;rsquo;s tournament, they introduced a mini competition: build something in Lego related to the strategy game Age of Empires 2. That&amp;rsquo;s when I got excited.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was hesitant about what to build, but eventually decided to dismantle my biggest set, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lego.com/en-us/product/lion-knights-castle-10305&#34;&gt;The Lion Knights Castle&lt;/a&gt; (10305). Perfect for a Donjon in Lego. I didn&amp;rsquo;t use an online tool, so it was really about looking at the picture and building the Donjon brick by brick.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-day hike Elspeet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/two-day-hike-elspeet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/two-day-hike-elspeet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About twice a year Patrick, a friend of mine, and I walk a two-day hike somewhere in the Netherlands. This fall it was the turn of Nunspeet and Elspeet. About 20km per day. Starting in Nunspeet, through Elspeet and so back to Nunspeet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The beauty of Nunspeet is that you can get off the train and walk into the Veluwe. You imagine yourself soon in the woods and beautiful moors. You also pass beautiful castles and the landscape is enormously diverse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A few seconds of real rest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/one-pair-seconds-real-rest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/one-pair-seconds-real-rest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Usually when I walk I am lost in thought. I see my surroundings but do not perceive it. For a long time I did not consciously realize this. By consciously dealing with this, I can walk with more peace and appreciation from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the past I have often experienced busy periods, mostly thinking about work, private life, myself and much more. Then when I went for a walk, all kinds of thoughts would haunt my mind, thoughts that were of no use to me, but also thoughts over which I seemed to have little control. So I started to delve into the fact that I could well be addicted to thinking, which we all really are a bit. By reading several books on the subject, I actually almost automatically came up with the idea of consciously observing when I am walking it. In fact, it&amp;rsquo;s a form of walking meditation, and yes, just with eyes open.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cable frustration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/the-frustration-of-cables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/the-frustration-of-cables/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For quite a few years I have had a Macbook with only USB-C ports, the standard of the future as far as I am concerned. Pretty soon after that, I figured I would only buy devices with USB-C connectivity from then on, but that went a little differently than expected.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, there turned out to be no e-reader with this connection, but since I read a lot I really needed one. The iPhone also proved to be a problem, the iPad happily went with USB-C, but the iPhone stuck with Lightning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Inner Critic in Landscape Photography</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/inner-critic-landschape-photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/inner-critic-landschape-photography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My mind plays with me. It tells me I&amp;rsquo;m not good enough, I&amp;rsquo;m not good enough in photography or to start a business. Landscapes are too difficult for me or my compositions are not strong enough.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the inner critic, a part of you that wants you to do the things you&amp;rsquo;ve always done. So new things are not on the agenda of the inner critic. To be honest, I just recently became aware of the inner critic. Before the awareness, I thought it was me, and it held me back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using ancient lenses as a backup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/old-lenses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/old-lenses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been using a very old manual lens on my Sony A7iii, and to be honest, I shot some of my best images from the last few months with this lens.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;figure class=&#34;c-media c-media--video&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;iframe&#xA;        src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7tBvgsv4RP8&#34;&#xA;        title=&#34;Wolf Maps video&#34;&#xA;        frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&#xA;        allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34;&#xA;        allowfullscreen&#xA;        &gt;&#xA;        &lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;l-single u-content&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I want to tell you why I&amp;rsquo;m using this lens and why gear is important, but not holy or something. Better an old lens than no lens at all. But first a little story about what happened!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>54 Dolmens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/54-hunebeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/54-hunebeds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Photographing 54 dolmens for a book being written. Quite a lot of work and planning, but with the right preparation it worked out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, I took notes on position, light and composition at almost all the dolmens. The most interesting hunebeds got a special note. There were also a number of hunebeds (especially in the Emmen area) that were simply too large to be photographed properly. At these dolmens I returned once more to photograph them with a drone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nikki the Heidewachtel 1 year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/nikki-the-heidewachtel-1-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/nikki-the-heidewachtel-1-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I loved dogs as a little boy and wanted to have one when I grow up. By now I am &amp;lsquo;big&amp;rsquo; and Nikki the Heidewachtel is already one year old. Time to look back on last year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-first-weeks&#34;&gt;The first weeks&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first few weeks Nikki was with us were very disappointing. I was warned beforehand that it could be tough, but apparently that wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough. Among other things, the crate was a thing. From day one we tried to make her comfortable in the crate, no forcing, lots of treats and a nice place. Still it didn&amp;rsquo;t work out, every time she had to go into the crate she would screech and roar. Sometimes up to more than an hour. And if it stopped for a moment you could still hear it, that sound creeps into your head. Still, keep ignoring the dog, because this is the only thing that works to get the dog used to the crate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Karwendel hut tour</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/karwendel-hut-tour/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/karwendel-hut-tour/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We slam the car doors shut, tie the laces of our mountain boots, throw our backpacks on our backs and set off towards the west. The 2016 hut tour is underway, we are hiking into the Karwendel Mountains of Austria.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In five days we walk from Vomp, near Innsbruck, in a round trip back to the starting point. Four mountain huts we will pass: the Lamsenjochhütte, the Falkenhütte, Karwendelhaus and Haulerangerhaus. Despite broken nights (we slept in dormitories with lots of snoring), the trek was relatively easy during the first three days. The fourth day it turned out there was a lot of ice on the summit so we walked an alternate route. The last day was a tough one where we expected to walk mostly downhill, but this was not the case at all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The rugged island of Madeira</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/the-rugged-island-madeira/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/the-rugged-island-madeira/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At 01:00 in the night we get up, which is quite inhuman, and drive to Schiphol Airport. After a smooth flight, we land on the short runway of the flower island of Madeira. It has been less than a week since 8% of the island&amp;rsquo;s nature burned down, so our trip feels a bit double. Still, we plan to make it a vacation without too many plans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An hour later we drive on our way to our first night&amp;rsquo;s stay, a Quinta in the northeastern part of the island. The landscape there is arid and dry, not many flowers to be found in this place. That evening we walk from the Quinta to the north side of the island (which is less than fifteen minutes walk) and arrive at beautiful cliffs where the rough sea laps against them. A setting sun, huge winds, but a beautiful location.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nikki 16 weeks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/nikki-16-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/nikki-16-weeks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By now Nikki has been with us for 8 weeks. Naughty, enthusiastic, but incredibly sweet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;c-photos-wrapper&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &lt;ul class=&#34;c-photos c-photos--square&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;          &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &lt;li class=&#34;c-photos__item c-photos__item--33 &#34;&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;            &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-0&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/nikki-16-weken/2.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;              &lt;img class=&#34;js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/nikki-16-weken/2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xA;              &#xA;            &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;        &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;          &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &lt;li class=&#34;c-photos__item c-photos__item--33 &#34;&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;            &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-0&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/nikki-16-weken/3.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;              &lt;img class=&#34;js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/nikki-16-weken/3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xA;              &#xA;            &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;        &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;          &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &lt;li class=&#34;c-photos__item c-photos__item--33 &#34;&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;            &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-0&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/nikki-16-weken/4.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;              &lt;img class=&#34;js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/nikki-16-weken/4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xA;              &#xA;            &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;        &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;l-single u-content&#34;&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pups born</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/puppies-born/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/puppies-born/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last January 8, the puppies were born from Venna. A beautiful Heidewachtel van &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.westpolderjagers.nl/&#34;&gt;de Westpolderjagers&lt;/a&gt;. 8 puppies, of which 5 females and 3 males. We may bring home a female in March.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A week ago we went to see the little puppies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;c-photos-wrapper&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &lt;ul class=&#34;c-photos &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;          &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &lt;li class=&#34;c-photos__item c-photos__item--40 &#34;&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;            &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-0&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/pups-geboren/2.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;              &lt;img class=&#34;js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/pups-geboren/2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xA;              &#xA;            &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;        &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;          &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &lt;li class=&#34;c-photos__item c-photos__item--60 &#34;&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;            &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-0&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/pups-geboren/3.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;              &lt;img class=&#34;js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/pups-geboren/3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xA;              &#xA;            &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;        &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;          &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &lt;li class=&#34;c-photos__item c-photos__item--60 &#34;&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;            &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-0&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/pups-geboren/4.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;              &lt;img class=&#34;js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/pups-geboren/4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xA;              &#xA;            &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;        &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;          &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &lt;li class=&#34;c-photos__item c-photos__item--40 &#34;&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;            &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-0&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/pups-geboren/5.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;              &lt;img class=&#34;js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/pups-geboren/5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xA;              &#xA;            &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;        &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;l-single u-content&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Next week we will visit the kennel again, when they will be four weeks old and already a lot more active.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Africa Highlights</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/highlights-south-africa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/highlights-south-africa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;South Africa, a land of contrasts. In one country you will find desert, grand forests, poverty and wealth. Starting November 10, I traveled to South Africa with my father. For him the second time after 32 years, for me the first time. Herewith my highlights of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;kruger-park-game-drive&#34;&gt;Kruger Park game drive&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our guide gets into the jeep and we are the first to drive into the Kruger Park. It is 5 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning and at a brisk speed he tells us that we are going to look for the big cats first. Water buffalo, zebras and rhinos we drive past until we come to a pride of lions. One by one the cubs and mothers walk by and they are close, very close.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Refresh: The meetup for designers and front end developers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/refresh-the-meetup-for-designers-and-front-end-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/refresh-the-meetup-for-designers-and-front-end-developers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;c-photos-wrapper&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &lt;ul class=&#34;c-photos &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;          &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &lt;li class=&#34;c-photos__item c-photos__item--100 &#34;&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;            &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-0&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/refresh-the-meetup-for-designers-and-front-end-developers/refresh-the-meetup-for-designers-and-front-end-developers.png&#34;&gt;&#xA;              &lt;img class=&#34;js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/refresh-the-meetup-for-designers-and-front-end-developers/refresh-the-meetup-for-designers-and-front-end-developers.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xA;              &#xA;            &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;        &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;l-single u-content&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of great meet-ups in Groningen like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/PyGrunn/&#34;&gt;PyGrunn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/SMC050/&#34;&gt;SMC050&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Groningen-rb/&#34;&gt;Groningen.rb&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Drupal-Noord-Meetup/&#34;&gt;Drupal Noord&lt;/a&gt; and more. But meet-ups for designers and front-end developers are hard to find.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s why &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ronvandegraaf&#34;&gt;Ron van de Graaf&lt;/a&gt; and I organized several meet-ups for this group of people last year. Within each session we watched video conference talks including those of &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/aarron&#34;&gt;Aarron Walter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/monteiro&#34;&gt;Mike Monteiro&lt;/a&gt;. This led the evening to natural and good discussions. During these first trial sessions we invited people from HackerOne, Spindle, Blixx, Concept7 and Studio Wolf. After a few drinks it was clear to us this meet-up needed a follow-up. That&amp;rsquo;s how Refresh was founded in the summer of 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Onlands in the evening</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/onlands-in-the-evening/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/onlands-in-the-evening/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last time I could not capture the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/en/blog/the-gold-of-the-uncountries/&#34;&gt;sunset in the Onlanden&lt;/a&gt; properly because of the lack of clouds. This time I succeeded a lot better, although I had continuous rain showers coming over me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;c-photos-wrapper&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &lt;ul class=&#34;c-photos &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;          &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &lt;li class=&#34;c-photos__item c-photos__item--50 &#34;&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;            &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/onlanden-in-de-avond/2.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;              &lt;img class=&#34;js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/onlanden-in-de-avond/2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xA;              &#xA;            &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;        &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;          &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &lt;li class=&#34;c-photos__item c-photos__item--50 &#34;&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;            &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/onlanden-in-de-avond/3.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;              &lt;img class=&#34;js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/onlanden-in-de-avond/3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xA;              &#xA;            &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;        &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;          &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &lt;li class=&#34;c-photos__item c-photos__item--50 &#34;&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;            &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/onlanden-in-de-avond/4.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;              &lt;img class=&#34;js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/onlanden-in-de-avond/4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xA;              &#xA;            &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;        &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;          &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &lt;li class=&#34;c-photos__item c-photos__item--50 &#34;&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;            &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/onlanden-in-de-avond/5.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;              &lt;img class=&#34;js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/onlanden-in-de-avond/5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xA;              &#xA;            &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;        &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;          &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &lt;li class=&#34;c-photos__item c-photos__item--100 &#34;&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;            &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/onlanden-in-de-avond/6.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;              &lt;img class=&#34;js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/onlanden-in-de-avond/6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xA;              &#xA;            &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;        &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;l-single u-content&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;neutral-density&#34;&gt;Neutral Density&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the pictures below I used an ND (Neutral Density) filter to get the shutter speed around the minute which gives you a nice effect in the clouds and in this case the water becomes very smooth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gold of the Onlands</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/the-gold-of-the-uncountries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/the-gold-of-the-uncountries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once again I run up the stairs; this time to grab my tripod. I am in a hurry. The sky looks beautiful and I need to make it to the Onlands. I attach my Canon 24mm F2.8 to the camera, throw my backpack over my shoulder and walk to the car.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The moment I get in the car all sorts of thoughts spin through my head. Will I be in time for a nice sky? What&amp;rsquo;s the best spot for a landscape photo tonight? Where do I park the car? Especially the first question always turns out to be a problem; nature does what it wants anyway.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fellowship of the Hardangervidda</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/the-fellowship-of-the-hardangervidda/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/the-fellowship-of-the-hardangervidda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The wind pushes me so hard to the side that I have to fight against it with my trekking poles. It feels like a wind force of nine, and even a 14‑kilogram backpack doesn’t help me stay upright easily. Meanwhile, it starts to rain, and the downpour continues for several hours. The puddles grow larger with too many pebbles, and unfortunately, my hiking boots fill up with water. The six of us are trekking through the Hardangervidda in Norway, and it’s magnificent!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Element Queries</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/element-queries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/element-queries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;c-photos-wrapper&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &lt;ul class=&#34;c-photos &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;          &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &lt;li class=&#34;c-photos__item c-photos__item--100 &#34;&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;            &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-0&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/element-queries/element-queries.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;              &lt;img class=&#34;js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/element-queries/element-queries.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xA;              &#xA;            &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;        &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;l-single u-content&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a few years now we&amp;rsquo;ve been creating responsive websites. We do this with the famous media queries, and they are awesome. But what if we could do things a bit smarter, for instance with element queries? Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into our current method first, media queries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-media-query&#34;&gt;The media query&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A media query can define a breakpoint. On a breakpoint we can change our design. In responsive design we usually work with height and/or width changes based on the viewport of our browser.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choose a Friend</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/choose-a-friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/choose-a-friend/</guid>
      <description>&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;c-photos-wrapper&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &lt;ul class=&#34;c-photos &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;          &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &lt;li class=&#34;c-photos__item c-photos__item--100 &#34;&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;            &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-0&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/kies-een-vriend/kies-een-vriend-2.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;              &lt;img class=&#34;js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/kies-een-vriend/kies-een-vriend-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xA;              &#xA;            &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;        &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;l-single u-content&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After we had decided to take care of a dog, we encountered several questions. Should we get a shelter dog? Or should we go to a breeder? Male or female? After doing some reading, we quickly decided to choose a female from a breeder. A female tends to be calmer, and if it’s your first dog, that works out well. Although you must be cautious with a female during her heat—as she might then want to find a mate—a big question still remained: what breed?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Story of the Train</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/het-verhaal-van-de-trein/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/het-verhaal-van-de-trein/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Directly across from me, two women are talking about the hospital—one with a very high-pitched voice, while the other looks disinterestedly at her phone, nodding occasionally. The man behind them is clearly irritated and takes another sip of his kiosk coffee. Next to him, a woman is on the phone with her current client; she seems happy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The train is a wellspring of inspiration. I can easily imagine writers on the train inventing the characters they seek—a quirky nose, a high voice, a full beard with bits of bread in it, a 16-year-old boy with too much gel in his hair, or someone with a distinctive scent. When you look closely at a person, you catch a glimpse of their life. Is it someone with children—perhaps in primary school or even in vocational school? Maybe the child, by accident, never got a swimming certificate, or is addicted to double vla. What might his friends be like? Someone with long hair, short hair, or no hair at all? A hat? Is he or she ill? Is it a chronic condition or does it pass quickly? What will the man do when he gets off the train—turn left or right? Or does he work at the station in the bistro? And with whom does he go home in the evening? Is it an old-fashioned or a modern house? Or is there even a house at all?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weight Obsession</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/weight-obsession/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/weight-obsession/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A tiny sleeping mat weighing 350 grams costs 150 euros. A large sleeping mat weighing 800 grams costs only about ten euros. A sleeping bag weighing 1200 grams or 750 grams? I won’t even mention the price difference. Oh, and I’m definitely taking along a tripod weighing 1.6 kilograms!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This coming summer, I will be exploring the highlands of Norway—the Hardangervidda nature reserve—with five other enthusiasts. Over the course of seven days, we will hike from Finse to Odda carrying our full backpacks. This year, it isn’t a hut-to-hut trip with luxurious hot meals, a reasonably good bed, and friendly people, but rather a trek with tents, small stoves, and other gear that will keep us alive. I want to hike lightly and enjoy the surroundings instead of huffing and puffing under a weight that’s unbelievable. That’s why I started paying attention to every gram.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lacey, Nikki and Bas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/lacey-nikki-and-bas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/lacey-nikki-and-bas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;c-photos-wrapper&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &lt;ul class=&#34;c-photos &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;          &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &lt;li class=&#34;c-photos__item c-photos__item--100 &#34;&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;            &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-0&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/lacey-nikki-en-bas/lacey-nikki-en-bas.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;              &lt;img class=&#34;js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/lacey-nikki-en-bas/lacey-nikki-en-bas.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xA;              &#xA;            &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;        &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;l-single u-content&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a little boy, every year I would travel south with my little sister and my parents to Landgraaf. There, friends of ours lived with their dog Lacey. Lacey was a Beagle with just a bit too short legs and a nose that was a little too small.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During a long walk with Lacey through the hilly landscapes of Limburg, Frans, her owner, warned us to be cautious around wild animals: &amp;ldquo;If she sees a rabbit, it might very well be that we lose her for a while—after all, Lacey is a hunting dog.&amp;rdquo; When Lacey was out in nature, it almost seemed as if she were laughing, which of course doesn’t make any sense, but you could tell that she was at her best. She loved exploring and leaping through the tall grass, all the while keeping a watchful eye on both her owner and the wildlife.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sketch vs Photoshop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/sketch-vs-photoshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/sketch-vs-photoshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;c-photos-wrapper&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &lt;ul class=&#34;c-photos &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;          &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &#xA;        &#xA;  &#xA;        &lt;li class=&#34;c-photos__item c-photos__item--100 &#34;&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;          &#xA;            &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-0&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/sketch-vs-photoshop/sketch-vs-photoshop.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;              &lt;img class=&#34;js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/sketch-vs-photoshop/sketch-vs-photoshop.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xA;              &#xA;            &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;          &#xA;        &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;      &#xA;      &#xA;    &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;l-single u-content&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since about a year I&amp;rsquo;m working with &lt;a href=&#34;http://bohemiancoding.com/sketch/&#34;&gt;Sketch by Bohemian Coding&lt;/a&gt;. For those unknown with Sketch, it’s a Mac application for interface design. Before using Sketch we mainly used Adobe Photoshop at Studio Wolf, a tool most of you probably know of.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After not using Photoshop for a year (for Interface design that is) we’ve been asked to use Photoshop for a project because a client desired so (mostly because their technical party doesn’t use Sketch).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to set up an inline SVG sprite</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/how-to-set-up-an-inline-svg-sprite/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/how-to-set-up-an-inline-svg-sprite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Years ago I worked with large PNG sprites with tons of icons, logo’s and other layout supporting images. Simply because it was the most efficient way to load images with the smallest amount of connections. Today SVG is supported by all major browsers. In this article I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how to set up an inline SVG sprite.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Back in the days designing for the web was hard. We had to use sprites for almost everything. Fortunately the web grew better. CSS transformations, border radiuses, gradients and much more fancy techniques entered our workspace. Now, only icons were left in the PNG sprite.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disconnected</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/disconnected/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/disconnected/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rocks, lots of rocks—I’m at nearly 3000 meters altitude, clambering over a massive boulder that looks like Steve Ballmer’s head, bald and imposing. With my walking stick, I can just manage to wedge it into the next rock to pull myself up. Success—I’m standing with both feet on Mr. Ballmer. I catch my breath.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ahead of me, two friends are clambering along: one with a neat black backpack weighing 11 kg, and the other with a half-sagging bright red backpack weighing 12 kg. They’re faster than I am, but that’s alright. It’s my own fault—I tend to look around too much, just as I keep gazing at “Steve.” To my left, I see the highest peak in the area, the Hochgall, at about 3436 meters. To my right, a gigantic expanse of snow makes me feel incredibly small.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My 6 hour workday</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/my-6-hour-workday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/my-6-hour-workday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For about two years now I’ve been wandering around with the idea of working 6 hour days. 4 weeks ago the time felt right to try this experiment. From the 17th of November until the 12th of December I worked 6 hours a day, no more. Okay, to be honest, one day we had a deadline and launch party of the new Voys website, but all the other days were around 6 hours.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Appelbergen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/appelbergen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/appelbergen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To test my Canon 6D&amp;rsquo;s video quality and capabilities, I made a short video in the Appelbergen. It was early in the morning and the sun was truly beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;figure class=&#34;c-media c-media--video&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;iframe&#xA;        src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/T636cwPuEUo&#34;&#xA;        title=&#34;Wolf Maps video&#34;&#xA;        frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&#xA;        allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34;&#xA;        allowfullscreen&#xA;        &gt;&#xA;        &lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;l-single u-content&#34;&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eating the hamburger on the mobile web</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/eating-the-hamburger-on-the-mobile-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/eating-the-hamburger-on-the-mobile-web/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People have been using the hamburger-icon on websites since &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.placeit.net/history-of-the-hamburger-icon/&#34;&gt;at least the 1990’s&lt;/a&gt;. Since responsive websites and mobile apps have grown in popularity, usage of the hamburger-icon has exploded. We’re searching for a better mobile navigation for the web and would like to share our ideas and the issues we’re encountering. Today’s issue is iOS Safari.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;navigating-in-apps&#34;&gt;Navigating in Apps&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lately there’s been a lot of &lt;a href=&#34;http://mor10.com/hamburger-bad/&#34;&gt;discussion about the icon&lt;/a&gt;. A short while ago &lt;del&gt;Apple also wrote a piece&lt;/del&gt; on the usage of the hamburger as a way of navigating.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blind: Fountain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/blind-fountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/blind-fountain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My father on the left and my mother on the right — they support me as the three of us take a stroll through the large hall on the east side of the building. I hear people passing by, yet I feel alone. Alone with my parents. There isn’t even anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A sign, very close by — we walk past it. I ask my mother, “Is this sign yellow?” while she shakes her head and tells me that it’s red, bright red. Red is one of the colors that fades away the quickest when vision is impaired.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blind: Inheritance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/blind-inheritance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/blind-inheritance/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blind: Sandwich</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/blind-sandwich/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/blind-sandwich/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wake up after spending my first night at the UMCG. Within half an hour, the nurse comes by with my first hospital breakfast. I hear her cheerfully say good morning as she places a tray on the bedside table that now hovers over my bed. After thanking her, I grab a sandwich and take a bite. It’s dry, with no spread. I’m supposed to spread it myself, which I can’t do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blind: Summary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/blind-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/blind-summary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was February 2006 and I was about to take my exams as a 15-year-old at VMBO TL in Groningen. Slowly, I began to lose my sight. After an incorrect diagnosis by the general practitioner and a full day of tests at the hospital (blood tests, CT scan, neurological exam, spinal tap), I was sent home. That, however, was not enough.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Within three days, I was hooked up to an IV with the strongest dose of prednisone for adults at the UMCG. I couldn’t see anything anymore. After speaking with many doctors and undergoing numerous tests, my sight started to return after a few days. The symptoms never fully came back, though the fear of them has always lingered a bit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Light, lighter, lightest, lightestest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/light-lighter-lightest-lightestest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/light-lighter-lightest-lightestest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Color variables in Sass or Less can be very tricky to maintain and extend. In this note, I explain the problems we encountered and how we solved them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I believe that working with variables is important because it drastically improves the &lt;strong&gt;consistency within a web application&lt;/strong&gt;—especially when working in a team with two or more designers. For example, one designer might use &lt;code&gt;lighten($gray-light, 10%)&lt;/code&gt; while another uses &lt;code&gt;lighten($gray-light, 7%)&lt;/code&gt;. This leads to subtle differences everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cycles: Design in an Iterative Workflow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/cycles-design-in-an-iterative-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/cycles-design-in-an-iterative-workflow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;c-media &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img class=&#34;c-media__image js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/cycles-design-in-een-iteratieve-werkwijze/cycles-design-in-een-iteratieve-werkwijze.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For years, we worked on our projects using the waterfall method: concept, sketch, design, front-end, back-end, and handover. It’s a solid method because the foundation of any process is to communicate concrete steps effectively. However, as you grow in projects and experience, you gradually realize that you’re looking for a more flexible and engaging process. Before I continue discussing this new process, let me share a bit of history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expectation Management for Designers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/expectation-management-for-designers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/expectation-management-for-designers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;c-media &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img class=&#34;c-media__image js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/verwachtingsmanagement-voor-designers/verwachtingsmanagement-voor-designers.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As designers, we have to deal with clients’ expectations. Even before they approach you, they already have an idea of what the final product should be, even if they don’t realize it. This is human nature and is embedded in our subconscious.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These expectations are not always in our favor as designers. For example, you agree with the client to discuss the project. A few weeks later, you present the Photoshop design. The client responds by saying that he finds it terrible. So, you end up back at the drawing board.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Community and Miscommunications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/community-and-miscommunications/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/community-and-miscommunications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;c-media &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img class=&#34;c-media__image js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/community-en-miscommunicaties/community-en-miscommunicaties.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bringing people together online has always been a passion of mine. Given my affinity for &lt;a href=&#34;http://aljanscholtens.nl/gallery&#34;&gt;photography&lt;/a&gt;, it would be amazing to combine the online gathering of people with photography. A community where people discuss various aspects; how can a photo be improved in terms of lighting and composition? Which lens should I buy? Should I go professional or not?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have always been intrigued by constructive criticism, or in other words, feedback. Telling someone in a positive way how they can improve their photo—both offering constructive advice and highlighting what works well—is something I could never find online. A few years ago, that’s when the idea of &lt;del&gt;Focussion&lt;/del&gt; was born.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collaboration tools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/collaboration-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/collaboration-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;c-media &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img class=&#34;c-media__image js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/collaboration-tools/collaboration-tools.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At Studio Wolf, we are constantly on the lookout for great tools that can enhance both efficiency and quality. Below, I will discuss three key collaboration tools that we use on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;dropbox-for-business&#34;&gt;Dropbox (for business)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One important tool for us is &lt;a href=&#34;http://dropbox.com/&#34;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt;. It ensures that all our files (PSDs, proposals, images) are stored in one place—and that’s essential.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shortly before Kris joined our team at the beginning of 2012, we faced the following challenge: how can we continue working on a project immediately if the responsible designer is on vacation or otherwise absent?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance is design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/performance-is-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/performance-is-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;c-media &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img class=&#34;c-media__image js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/performance-is-design/performance-is-design.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The WiFi connection on the train is too slow, so you access a website with your slightly faster 3G connection. The website doesn’t load quickly, but you eventually get there—albeit not with much enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, the average webpage is &lt;strong&gt;1MB&lt;/strong&gt; in size, which is simply too much. We assumed that internet connections had become faster. That’s true, but we forgot about mobile connections. A 1MB page is too large, and in most cases, it’s the result of sheer laziness from designers and developers, myself included. This has changed significantly over time, and I have become aware of the importance of good performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distraction Makes You Dumb</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/distraction-makes-you-dumb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/distraction-makes-you-dumb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;c-media &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img class=&#34;c-media__image js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/afleiding-maakt-dom/afleiding-maakt-dom.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once upon an ordinary Saturday, I wanted to continue reading the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steve_Jobs_%28book%29&#34;&gt;biography of Steve Jobs&lt;/a&gt;. While reading, I realized that I still needed to print out concert tickets for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.katzenjammer.no/&#34;&gt;Katzenjammer&lt;/a&gt; for that evening. But the ink had run out. While replacing the ink, I spilled it on my trousers. I quickly cleaned it up and printed the tickets.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I curled back up on the couch with the book and resumed reading on page 35. There, I read that Steve lets ink splatter on his books. A grin spread across my face. I grabbed my iPad to share it with my friends. Distracted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2012: A Spectacular Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/2012-a-spectacular-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/2012-a-spectacular-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;c-media &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img class=&#34;c-media__image js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/2012-een-spectaculair-jaar/2012-een-spectaculair-jaar.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The past year, as it has been for many, was a busy one. It was marked by a lot of change and hard work. Since we all love end-of-year overviews, here is our year in review.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;kris&#34;&gt;Kris&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It all began in February. Kris joined Studio Wolf as an interface designer. It was a big step for us. Hiring our first employee is said to be the hardest step, so that really makes a difference. The three of us tackled it together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Device Lab Groningen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/open-device-lab-groningen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/open-device-lab-groningen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;c-media &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img class=&#34;c-media__image js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/open-device-lab-groningen/open-device-lab-groningen.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Testing whether your responsive website or native app works well can be challenging in a small team or as a freelancer. For this, you need devices. You can either procure them yourself or look for a location that offers a wide range of devices for testing. In that case, an &lt;a href=&#34;http://mobile.smashingmagazine.com/2012/09/24/establishing-an-open-device-lab/&#34;&gt;Open Device Lab&lt;/a&gt; would be very useful. Unfortunately, such a facility is currently lacking in Groningen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every day we work on responsive websites and web applications. Testing becomes especially difficult when everyone in the office only has an iPhone or iPad. That’s why I frequently rely on family and friends to test on Windows Phone and Android devices. Far from ideal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sass Placeholders</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/sass-placeholders/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/sass-placeholders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;c-media &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img class=&#34;c-media__image js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/sass-placeholders/sass-placeholders.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A common problem with HTML is the number of classes we use, for example &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;product product-hat&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. Duplicating CSS also happens too often in order to achieve the desired result. There is a solution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the &lt;a href=&#34;http://smashingconf.com/&#34;&gt;Smashing Conference&lt;/a&gt; in Freiburg, Nicole Sullivan (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/stubbornella&#34;&gt;@Stubornella&lt;/a&gt;) talked about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://sass-lang.com/docs/yardoc/file.SASS_REFERENCE.html#placeholder_selectors_&#34;&gt;SASS placeholder&lt;/a&gt; (available since SASS 3.2). The placeholder is a type of selector that does not appear in the compiled CSS output.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Where we would normally use &lt;code&gt;.selector&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;#selector&lt;/code&gt;, we now use &lt;code&gt;%selector&lt;/code&gt;. The &lt;code&gt;%product&lt;/code&gt; below does nothing on its own; it does not appear in the CSS output.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bye bye Photoshop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/bye-bye-photoshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/bye-bye-photoshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;c-media &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img class=&#34;c-media__image js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/weg-met-photoshop/weg-met-photoshop.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;      &lt;figcaption class=&#34;c-media__caption&#34;&gt;Admission ticket for Smashing Conference in Freiburg&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vitaly Friedman and Marc Thiele of &lt;a href=&#34;http://smashingmagazine.com/&#34;&gt;Smashing Magazine&lt;/a&gt; (a leading blog on design and development) made the first &lt;a href=&#34;http://smashingconf.com/&#34;&gt;Smashing Conference&lt;/a&gt; possible in Freiburg. We were there.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With 16 trendy speakers, including Oliver Reichenstein of iA Writer, Aarron Walter of Mailchimp, and Christian Heilmann of Mozilla, the two days were truly inspiring. Thanks to the great talks and an informal atmosphere, time flew by. By the way, Freiburg is a beautiful city. Tim is still fascinated by the little streams that run through it. And during the breaks, there were of course plenty of bratwurst and bockwurst bites.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coloring with Sass</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/coloring-with-sass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/coloring-with-sass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When we color our designs with CSS, a very convenient way to achieve transparency is the alpha channel using the &lt;code&gt;rgba()&lt;/code&gt; function. This function requires four parameters: a red, green and blue value and an alpha value. For example: &lt;code&gt;rgba(78, 85, 58, 0.5)&lt;/code&gt; where we generate a Studio Wolf green color with a 50% transparency.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The only thing is: you never work with RGB values on the web. You work with hexadecimal colors. Fortunately for us, we have Sass. Sass automatically transforms your hex code to a valid RGB input. We can use the &lt;code&gt;rgba()&lt;/code&gt; function in Sass like this: &lt;code&gt;rgba(#4e553a, 0.5)&lt;/code&gt;. Sass will then transform this to &lt;code&gt;rgba(78, 85, 58, 0.5)&lt;/code&gt; for us. And we all live happily ever after.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retina data conflict</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/retina-data-conflict/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/retina-data-conflict/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;c-media &#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img class=&#34;c-media__image js-lazy&#34; data-original=&#34;/blog/retina-data-conflict/retina-data-conflict.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Retina display: a screen with four times as many pixels in the same area, now available for iPad and, since last week, the MacBook Pro. Text and images look absolutely stunning on these screens, but not everyone is ready for it yet. Interface designers need to consider several factors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;mobile-internet&#34;&gt;Mobile Internet&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Four times as many pixels mean that images in a web application become twice as large in terms of dimensions. An image that’s twice as large has a significantly bigger file size. Where a photo might normally be around 100 kilobytes, for Retina it becomes about three to four times bigger. This is a big impact on your mobile data, especially in places like the Netherlands where mobile data plans are limited.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
